<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Mark's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-16T14:06:58-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://marklee22.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Lee]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[marklee22@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Marathon Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2014/08/03/the-marathon-experience/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-03T12:40:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2014/08/03/the-marathon-experience</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A week ago, I finished my first ever marathon with a painful time of 3:30:42. I&rsquo;m ecstatic. It&rsquo;s about 15 minutes faster than I hoped for, or a little more than ~30 seconds faster per mile than what I trained for. Despite that, 42 seconds is going to haunt me for quite some time. A lot of people have asked me what it was like, so I decided I&rsquo;d write a recount of events of the whole thing from start to finish.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-08-03/marathon_course.png"></p>

<h2>Pre-Race</h2>

<h3>3:15am</h3>

<p>For some reason I wake up at 3am; an hour before my alarm. As I get up and change, I hear my roommate returning home from the bars which I find hilarious. I prep my breakfast of a bagel with peanut butter, a banana, and a blue Gatorade. I fill up my camelbak, put in my contacts, and hop on my Vespa to pick-up my bib from my work since they picked them up for us the day before.</p>

<h3>4:30am</h3>

<p>I am told I should pick my bib up from the bus coming from LinkedIn HQ in Mountain View between Howard and Harrison. Well, I get there on time and low and behind, no one is here. And it&rsquo;s still pitch dark. I&rsquo;m not going to lie, I am a little worried that they are going to be late and I won&rsquo;t have my bib in time. Like every other time I worry though, it all works out and the bus arrives 10 minutes later.</p>

<h3>4:50am</h3>

<p>My co-worker&rsquo;s boyfriend works right by the start line, so I decide to take up his offer of using their bathrooms before the race. I&rsquo;ll skip the details, but two words: life saver.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-08-03/start-line.jpg"></p>

<h3>5:15am</h3>

<p>I arrive at the RUN365 tent and I start to feel the nerves. There is an absurd amount of people here and the sun hasn&rsquo;t even come up. I&rsquo;m starting to get nervous about things like not hydrating enough, only having 3 hours of sleep, and whether I&rsquo;m going to have to use the bathroom during the race. My official wave is wave 4 which had an average pace of 9:00 &ndash; 9:30, but instead decide that I&rsquo;d rather start at the pace I plan to run, which is 8:15 &ndash; 8:45 in wave 2.</p>

<h3>5:30am</h3>

<p>The first wave is off. I hop the fence in our private booth to jump in the wave and target the 3:45 total time pacing group. I turn on my marathon playlist that I made and start my Nike+ run tracker. I exit the gates 4 minutes later after the gun and think to myself, &ldquo;well, here goes nothing&rdquo;.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-08-03/pre-race.jpg" width="250" height="325"></p>

<h2>The Race</h2>

<h3>Mile 4 (The Marina)</h3>

<p>At this point, I&rsquo;m in the Marina chugging at about an 8:15min/mile pace. I&rsquo;m still with the 3:45 pacing group and can&rsquo;t help but notice that there are a lot of cute girls in my group and they are all super fit. But I didn&rsquo;t sign up for this race to meet women. I signed up to cross this off my bucket list AND beat my friends&#8217; times. I&rsquo;ve been taking one shot block every mile at this point and start to feel more tired than I usually feel at mile 4. I assume it&rsquo;s the lack of sleep more so than the faster pace.</p>

<h3>Mile 5 (The Hill before the GG Bridge)</h3>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know what hit me, but my mentality changes from this point forward. I start going up the hill before the bridge and something in my mind clicks: I want to run faster up this hill than the pacing group. I have been running these hills for 2 months and feel like I can maintain my pace going up them. I slowly start to speed up and leave them behind.</p>

<h3>Mile 9 (The GG Bridge)</h3>

<p>Coming back over the bridge, there&rsquo;s a slight downhill. I decide that I should try and take advantage of the grade and start to elongate my strides and run a bit faster. At this point, I am consistently passing people and the groups have thinned out significantly. Every water station, I grab one cup electrolytes and two cups water to save the water in my camelbak for the remaining hills/end of the race. I still feel tired, but I tell myself the hardest part is over and there&rsquo;s a long downhill coming up.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-08-03/gg-bridge.jpg" width="250" height="325"></p>

<h3>Mile 13 (GG Park)</h3>

<p>I don&rsquo;t feel good anymore. The smiles for the cameras have disappeared and I feel soaked in sweat from head to toe. I&rsquo;m doubting that I&rsquo;ll be able to finish the race at this pace and I should slow down, but I don&rsquo;t. I just tell myself instead that I&rsquo;m halfway done and I just need to get through GG park to get to the flat parts of the race where I&rsquo;ll be fine.</p>

<h3>Mile 14 (GG Park)</h3>

<p>My Mom and her fiance said they&rsquo;d be here. At the mile marker, they aren&rsquo;t here, so I assume they must be further down the road. My Nike tracker is telling me that I&rsquo;m running at a 7:58 mile pace, so I now know I&rsquo;m on target to be below 3:30 and keep trying to bring that time down as the race goes on. About half a mile later I see my folks. They aren&rsquo;t ready at all and when I wave at them, they scramble out of surprise to take a photo and show me the big heads they made of me. I give my Mom a hug and then sprint back into the race to make up for the lost time.</p>

<h3>Mile 15 (GG Park)</h3>

<p>More hills! I can&rsquo;t believe how many god damn hills there are in this course. I&rsquo;ve run this part before, but haven&rsquo;t since my last long run of 24 miles three weeks ago. Surprisingly, I see the fastest guy in my training group ahead of me who said he was going for sub 3:30 before the race. I walk up behind him and say, &ldquo;I told you I&rsquo;d catch you&rdquo;, and pass him. Yeah, I know, I&rsquo;m kind of a dick, but in my defense, I said to him that I might catch him later. I didn&rsquo;t actually mean it when I said it though.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-08-03/gg-park.jpg" width="250" height="325"></p>

<h3>Mile 19 (Panhandle)</h3>

<p>Holy balls, I&rsquo;m out of the park! Thank god because I only have one pack of shot bloks left and my legs feel really heavy. Oh wait&hellip;no, I don&rsquo;t have those shot bloks because they apparently fell out of your camelbak. I panic a little because I feel like they give me a huge burst of energy everytime I eat one. Most likely it is pyschological, but luckily I remembered there is a GU station coming up in the Haight and I could just grab some food/energy there instead.</p>

<h3>Mile 23 (Potrero Hill)</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m cramping up in my hammys and calves. It&rsquo;s not to the point where I can&rsquo;t walk, but it&rsquo;s sharp pains that hit me sporadically. It doesn&rsquo;t hurt for more than a split second, and I imagine I look like something is shocking me in the ass. I&rsquo;ve eaten both my GUs at this point and figure I&rsquo;m about to run out of gas soon. However, I&rsquo;m counting down the miles at this point, telling myself I only have X left. Also every time I cramp up, I am verbally saying out loud: &ldquo;mind over body&rdquo; and &ldquo;you got this&rdquo;. There&rsquo;s another hill coming up on 16th and I feel like my body is about to break down going up this thing, but then miraculously Journey comes on with &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t Stop Believing&rdquo;. It is like Manifest destiny and I keep my pace going up the hill.</p>

<h3>Mile 25 (The Ballpark)</h3>

<p>This girl keeps passing me and I keep passing her. I&rsquo;m not sure if we&rsquo;re both ultra competitve or my pace is fluctuating up and down. I&rsquo;m feeling the cramps more often now, and am willing myself to the finish line. I see a lot of people walking and two guys who are laying on the ground from exhaustion. Nike+ is telling me my pace is 7:52, but I know it&rsquo;s wrong because the mile markers are about a quarter mile off. I am too tired to do the math in my head, but I think I&rsquo;ll be before 3:30, which is now the new goal.</p>

<p>As I look up, I see a guy in the distance from my running program who I wanted to run with pre-race but his target time was too fast for me. I am slowly catching up to him until I finally catch up to him to say, &ldquo;surprise, I guess I should have paced with you&rdquo;. His response was, &ldquo;damn dude, you&rsquo;re fast&rdquo;. We are passing the ballpark at this point and I ask if we&rsquo;re going to beat 3:30 and he says yes. I am assuming he started in front of me, so I trust him, but I still feel like I have some more left in the tank.</p>

<h3>Mile 26 (The Embarcadero)</h3>

<p>The sun is shining, you can hear the cheers in the distance, and I know I only have the equivalence of one lap around the track left. I pretty much feel a cramping sensation in one of my muscles every 10 seconds and it sucks. As I get closer to the finish line, the cheering makes my adrenaline start pumping. What&rsquo;s the most logical thing to do at this point? Well, it&rsquo;s quite simple&hellip;sprint. Yes, I kid you not. I decide to sprint the last 200m of the finish line. I wish I had a video because I felt like that is probably one of the most physically grueling things I&rsquo;ve ever done in my life and my face shows it.</p>

<h3>The Finish Line</h3>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-08-03/finish-line.jpg" width="250" height="325"></p>

<p>I cross the finish line with a half-smile across my face and slow down to a halt right after crossing. Well, immediately both my legs cramp up completely and I fall down to a crouch. I&rsquo;m sitting there for 2 seconds wondering if I can get up, but a lady comes up to me and asks if I&rsquo;m alright and that I need to move out of the way. I tell her ok and look up only to see someone wheeling a wheelchair towards me. I laugh and wave it off. Then hobble my way away from the finish line. Every step hurts at this point, I feel like my nipples were grinded with a cheese grader, and there&rsquo;s a knot in my shoulder like I&rsquo;ve never felt before. I stop my run tracker and see it&rsquo;s 3:31 and I can&rsquo;t help but think &ldquo;dammit&rdquo; at first, but I&rsquo;m still really proud of myself. I grab a boxed water and coconut water and then proceed to get brunch with my parents after.</p>

<div style="text-align: center;">
  <img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-08-03/post-race-1.jpg" width="250" height="325">
  <img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-08-03/post-race.jpg" width="250" height="325">
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>The question I always get is: <strong>Will you run a marathon again?</strong></p>

<p>Right now there&rsquo;s no specific race I want to do. I would say that if someone challenged me to one, I would definitely consider it, but I trained for more than half a year. That is an absurd amount of time looking back and I&rsquo;m honestly glad it&rsquo;s over so I can go back and pursue other goals of mine.</p>

<p>I will say that completing a marathon is no easy task. Qualifying for Boston is probably impossible. I&rsquo;m glad that I can cross this achievement off my bucket list, and am greatly thankful for all the support I got from my friends and family. Looking back, there were countless runs I did hungover on Saturday mornings. Many injuries that I had to overcome from bad shoes and running too fast. I think what I learned the most from this race is that I can do anything I put my mind to. Whether it&rsquo;s physically or mentally challenging, and I can only attribute that to the values instilled in me from my upbringing. If my family wasn&rsquo;t all so god damn competitive, there&rsquo;s no way I would have finished that without walking a bit. I now am the only one in my family to run a marathon and I&rsquo;m pretty sure it&rsquo;ll be that way for a while :). In closing, I just want to say once again, thanks all who supported me and I hope this blog post will inspire you to run a marathon in the future!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Year in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2014/06/04/year-in-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-04T20:46:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2014/06/04/year-in-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow! It&rsquo;s been a little less than a year since I began my new career as a Software Engineer here at Slideshare. I&rsquo;ve been meaning to get around to writing up a blog post about my life in the past few months, but just never got around to it. I spent a lot of time re-adjusting back to my life after graduating Hack Reactor in June last year, and then went 110% to make sure I did my best to not fuck up while I started my new career path into full-time development. <em>Spoiler alert:</em> It&rsquo;s been pretty fucking awesome!</p>

<h3>Life Updates</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;d say for a good 6 months, my work/life balance was a little out of whack, but I still managed to do some awesome things! Rather than go into the details, here&rsquo;s a short summary:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/sbones">Scott Bonebrake</a>, moved in with me here in North Beach.</li>
<li>My 7v7 Men&rsquo;s soccer team (Unathletic Madrid) and 11v11 coed soccer team (Ajax) won our league.</li>
<li>Some dude headbutted me while playing soccer in December and broke my nose.</li>
<li>Started training for the SF marathon this July.</li>
<li>Traveled to Boston, Vegas, LA, and Austin to visit friends and family.</li>
<li>Had an awesome three week vacation in South Korea and Malaysia with my #travelbros (FYI, we aren&rsquo;t bros. We use the term &lsquo;bro&rsquo; in a satirical way).</li>
</ul>


<h3>Work Updates</h3>

<p>Okay, time to get into the section where I brag about my technical and work achievments this coming year. I think the majority of the people who read this blog are either my good friends or someone who has stumbled upon it searching for information regarding the success of graduating from Hack Reactor or bootcamps. I want to just confirm to all the people on the ropes that it was hands down <strong>the best</strong> investment I&rsquo;ve made in my life, and I would make the same decision twice in a heartbeat.</p>

<p>I remember around this time last year, we were wrapping up HR and got a sense of everyone else&rsquo;s coding abilities. I never felt like I was the strongest programmer out of that class despite the fact I came in with the most experience and background. However, I knew I was one of the hardest working, and looking back at my life, that&rsquo;s something I&rsquo;ve always been good at. I can hypothesize all I want of where this trait originated from, but my best guess is my father worked his ass off and my older sister was/is way smarter than me. In metaphorical sports terms, my sister is like Lebron James while I am more like Tony Parker. She is just naturally gifted, while I had to put in the time and effort to become the <em>somewhat</em> intelligent man I am today.</p>

<p>Over my time here at Slideshare, I&rsquo;ve grown from a guy who was scared of stepping on people&rsquo;s toes&hellip;to being one of the leaders on my team. We&rsquo;ve grown a lot this year. Our office in SF has almost doubled in size and as shocking as it sounds, I&rsquo;ve become one of the &ldquo;old guys&rdquo;. Figuratively and literally. I analyze every codereview, interview candidates, mentor new college grads, and even get my own intern this month (yay?). All while deploying (and fixing) features that get viewed by millions every day.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s quite exciting still and it&rsquo;s a lot easier when your team is a great group of people to work with on a daily basis. Free lunch helps too. So does free sponsored events like Tough Mudders and Marathons. Seriously, working in tech is like being a spoiled child with endless access to candy. Thank god I have some self control to not eat Haribo gummi bears every day.</p>

<h4>Sitemap</h4>

<p>In my last update, I showed you my first big project I deployed. Well, since then, I&rsquo;ve had even more success. For starters, I spent a good amount of time understanding SEO and sitemaps. This is probably an underlooked topic by most when it comes to the web. Mostly because it&rsquo;s a big black box at Google with countless theories. For the non-technical, it&rsquo;s like the &ldquo;yellow pages&rdquo; of your website for bots to crawl all your links. I spent a lot of time purging all the &ldquo;bad links&rdquo; from it to make Google stop hating on us.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-06-04/sitemap.png" width="290" height="165"></p>

<h4>Mobile Swipe</h4>

<p>This is definitely my most exciting feature that took me a few months to build and perfect. We call it &ldquo;mobile swipe&rdquo;, but it&rsquo;s our mobile web player that brings native swiping to all our presentations. It&rsquo;s responsive and works on all devices leverages several JS libraries. So far the feedback has been very good and no matter where I am, I can show people on a mobile phone or tablet what I do here.</p>

<div style="text-align:center;">
  <img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-06-04/document_mobile_swipe.png" width="300" height="498">
  <img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-06-04/portrait.png" width="300" height="498">
</div>


<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-06-04/landscape_mobile_swipe.png" width="300" height="181"></p>

<h4>Edit My Uploads</h4>

<p>This is my most recent project. I redesigned our &ldquo;My Uploads&rdquo; page to be fully responsive and given it a design overhaul. We added some additional functionality to upload a Slideshare directly to your LinkedIn profile, but for the most part, we just made the page prettier.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/2014-06-04/new_edit_uploads.png" width="503" height="607"></p>

<h3>Last Words</h3>

<p>I feel like if I worked at a large corporation, there&rsquo;s no way I&rsquo;d have this many successful projects under my belt in less than a year. Maybe it&rsquo;s right place, right time; maybe not. One things for sure, I still plan to make a large impact on whatever I work on because programming is awesome and I would encourage anyone else to pursue it if you feel there&rsquo;s a passion for it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[1 month update]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/08/21/1-month-update/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-21T23:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/08/21/1-month-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bet you thought I was going to stop updating this once I got a job! You were * <strong>almost</strong> * right&hellip;</p>

<p>No, but seriously, I&rsquo;ve been really busy since starting my new job and regaining a social life. It just feels like my life is balanced again.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/one-month/books.png" width="500" height="400"></p>

<h3>Life Update</h3>

<p>So I guess one would ask: <em>Mark, what the hell have you been doing since wrapping up Hack Reactor and starting at Slideshare?</em></p>

<p>Well, I spent three weeks laying low and recharging my batteries after the 3 month marathon known as my tenure at Hack Reactor. Basically, a lot of sleeping in, a lot of socializing, and a good amount of reading Game of Thrones.</p>

<p>Now that I&rsquo;ve started work, I&rsquo;ve slowly started to get back into the groove of a schedule and it feels really good. I&rsquo;m back playing soccer 2-3 times a week, finally gave in and joined Tinder, picked up my Vespa from my friend, and even joined a few tech meetups here and there. Despite having more free time compared to when I was at HR, I feel like I&rsquo;m more busy than ever. Maybe it&rsquo;s just the fact that I basically ignored my friends for 3 months and have been playing catch up ever since.</p>

<h3>Job Update</h3>

<p>Since most of my traffic comes from searches about Hack Reactor and referrals from other people&rsquo;s blogs, I&rsquo;ll get into the more important updates. I can truly say at this point that I don&rsquo;t think I could have made a better choice for a place to work. It&rsquo;s the perfect balance of cool people, cool projects, and opportunity to learn and grow.</p>

<p>It was slow at first fixing small bugs to get familiar with the codebase and trying to remember how to program after taking 5 weeks off in between. I had an orientation at LinkedIn down in Mountain View for my first day. Then the following day joined my team in SF where I was told to deploy on my first day. No sweat, right? Although I was basically a monkey taking directions, I was able to knock it out of the park.</p>

<p>What I&rsquo;ve realized after 4 weeks of being a full-time programmer is the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>There&rsquo;s A LOT of code I didn&rsquo;t write. I spend a good amount of time tracing functions/callbacks all over the place</li>
<li>The huge importance of writing tests to cover the previous realization</li>
<li>Thank god I know a decent amount of git and BASH</li>
<li>Pixel perfect designs are really important!!!</li>
<li>Mobile responsiveness and Google Analytics are critical things to have working properly</li>
</ul>


<p>And on a less serious note:</p>

<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;m not particularly good at foosball when spinning is involved</li>
<li>Free soft drinks, beef jerky, and gummi bears are going to be the death of me</li>
<li>Perks at a big company are awesome</li>
<li>You do 20 pushups everytime your deploy breaks the site. &mdash; I&rsquo;ve done 40 so far</li>
</ul>


<h3>My First Change</h3>

<p>It took me a while, but my first &ldquo;real&rdquo; addition to the site is a share modal to share slideshows across your networks. My team is responsible for revamping the consumer experience for Slideshare, and we hope the new designs we&rsquo;re rolling out will improve the browse and share the experiences for our logged in users. You can find my new modal by clicking the &ldquo;Share&rdquo; button on a presentation <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/newlist/featured">here</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/one-month/modal-share.png" width="700" height="600"></p>

<p>Well, there&rsquo;s the update for now. I&rsquo;ll keep alternating between technical and non-technical posts in the future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Job! - Slideshare]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/06/30/new-job/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-30T23:29:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/06/30/new-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m announcing here that I have signed my offer letter and have a new job! Starting July 15th, I will be a Software Engineer for Slideshare/LinkedIn. <a href="http://slideshare.net">Slideshare</a> is an entity within LinkedIn, but their offices are located in LinkedIn&rsquo;s sales office here in local SF. I&rsquo;m ecstatic and excited about the opportunity as I will be tackling becoming a full stack + DevOps engineer.</p>

<div style="text-align: center;">
  <img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/new_job/slideshare.png" width="450" height="126">
  <img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/new_job/linkedin_logo.jpeg" width="450" height="126">
</div>


<p>Special thanks to everyone, especially <a href="http://hackreactor.com">Hack Reactor</a> for helping me achieve my goal. It&rsquo;s crazy to think 4 months ago when I started this blog that I achieved what I originally set out to do! Now that I have a job, I&rsquo;ll be focusing on programming again and hopefully never have to apply for jobs again in the near future. My duties will include heavy Javascript and Ruby/Rails, with a strong emphasis on testing. So expect a lot of Rails posts in the future!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Software Engineer Interview Process]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/06/24/the-interview-process/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-24T14:37:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/06/24/the-interview-process</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After going through so many interviews, I decided to blog about what the interviewing process is like for becoming a developer in this day and age. If you refer to my last post, I gave you the percentages of all the stages of each interview. Overall, I went through 30+ applications, 20 recruiter calls, 15-20 phone screens, and 11 on-site interviews. Clearly I am not great at interviewing as I received four offers total, but I do feel like I now understand the dos and don&#8217;ts of the interview process as a whole.</p>

<h3>Stage 1: The Resume</h3>

<p>The first step is to take your resume. Burn it. Then build it from the ashes. I&rsquo;m joking, but old Word Doc resumes are out. &ldquo;Adobe In-design&rdquo; templates are in. If you&rsquo;re not ready to pay for In-Design, there is an open-source alternative called <a href="http://scribus.net">scribus</a>, which I used to make my resume <a href="http://marklee22.github.io/resume">here</a>. I took two things into account when designing my resume:</p>

<ol>
<li>Attention spans are short. Less is more.</li>
<li>Seeing something different will probably stand out.</li>
</ol>


<p>Hack Reactor provides a lot of advice when creating resumes given the fact a lot of people don&rsquo;t have a technical work background related to programming. Luckily, I had a formal education and a job that performed technical duties, but readability was my main focus. Using my resume as an example, it was structured to have the stronger sections at the beginning and end (skills &amp; education), and then the weaker sections (work experience) in between. Some may argue my job is more important, but given the fact I did not do much programming on the job, I felt it less applicable, so YMMV.</p>

<h3>Stage 2: The Application</h3>

<p>This is straight forward. You want to send out as many applications as possible. At first I regretted doing this, but as most things go, things don&rsquo;t always pan out for your first or second choice and having a backup is a good idea. I noticed cover letters were optional most of the time, but if there&rsquo;s a box for it, <strong>always put a cover letter</strong>. I used a generic cover letter template that included the following:</p>

<ol>
<li>A brief intro of why I was interested in the position (1-2 sentences)</li>
<li>A brief description of my skills and previous work experience/school (3-4 sentences)</li>
<li>Links to my current projects I&rsquo;ve been working on</li>
<li>A note for them to refer to my resume for a list of my skills</li>
</ol>


<p>What you have to realize here is that engineers (unless you&rsquo;re applying to startups) are not the first person to read your resume. It&rsquo;s a non-technical resource, so they are looking for reasons to filter you out, so don&rsquo;t give them any.</p>

<h3>Stage 3: The Recruiter Call</h3>

<p>Depending on the size of the company, they may not have recruiters fielding this call, or may skip this call entirely. It&rsquo;s sole purpose is for them to weed you out. Now, what I&rsquo;m about to say is not indicative of what I did, but you could literally lie about or inflate your background/skills here. What I mean by this is the sole point here is to <strong>sell yourself to someone non-technical</strong>. They are gauging your background by looking for keywords and seeing whether or not you&rsquo;d be a good culture fit. Luckily for me, I&rsquo;ve had 5 years of consulting background where I was on the phone constantly, so I&rsquo;ve had some practice.</p>

<p>Overall, sell yourself, but still keep it honest. Just don&rsquo;t sell yourself short or speak negatively about yourself!</p>

<h3>Stage 4: The Phone Screen</h3>

<p>The purpose of the phone screen is to arrange a conversation between yourself and an engineer. The main purpose of this call is to gauge a candidate&rsquo;s technical knowledge by having an engineer ask basic questions that every ____ engineer should know. The format is pretty straightforward. You can expect a 45-60 minute phone call, and possibly a second one given the size of the company.</p>

<p>The format is:</p>

<ol>
<li>Introductions for both parties</li>
<li>Verbal questions from the engineer asking to describe simple web things that EVERY web developer should know</li>
<li>1-4 coding problems that are domain specific (algorithms, data structures, CSS, javascript, etc.)</li>
<li>A period to ask questions about the job/company</li>
</ol>


<p>This stage is heavy technically and less about selling yourself. Obviously, you&rsquo;ll want to ask some interesting questions at the end to show you&rsquo;re interested, but I&rsquo;m assuming that is obvious.</p>

<h3>Stage 5: The Take Home Problem</h3>

<p>This stage could be substituted for stage 4 or given in addition. It&rsquo;s what it sounds like though. An employer gives you a problem to code up in the language of your choice and submit it upon completion. These are usually projects ranging from 3-8 hours of work, and is pretty straight forward. A lot of times, the solutions can be found somewhere on the web, but it&rsquo;s still best to do it from scratch.</p>

<h3>Stage 6: The On-Site Interview</h3>

<p>Congratulations! You&rsquo;ve made it to the illustrious on-site interview. I could write an entire separate blog post about the on-site interview and how I don&rsquo;t agree with it&rsquo;s structure. However, there&rsquo;s a good chance, most of my biased opinion is based on the bitterness that I was not very good at these. Here&rsquo;s what I think will help calm your nerves about on-site interviews. They are simply evaluating two things: <strong>1) How you think 2) Are you a good culture fit.</strong></p>

<p>The format is pretty straight forward. It&rsquo;s anywhere from 3-6 hours. You meet the team and have several 45-60 minute sessions with 1-3 people (usually just 1) where you chat, whiteboard, and/or pair program problems together. Some interviewers are really good and some are really bad. What you need to focus on is your plan of attack and that&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;m going to write about.</p>

<p>What you should do when you whiteboard:</p>

<ol>
<li>Take your time and think about it before you write anything on the board</li>
<li>Draw a diagram of how your solution should work</li>
<li>Figure out the edge cases first so you can plan accordingly</li>
<li>Write out pseudocode so your interviewer knows what you&rsquo;re thinking</li>
<li>Write the actual code carefully</li>
<li>Refactor your code, if possible</li>
</ol>


<p>If your interviewer is good, he/she will help you along the way. If they don&rsquo;t and you don&rsquo;t know the answer, don&rsquo;t say &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know&rdquo;. Literally, just sit there in silence and think or say you would normally use google.</p>

<p>Overall, it&rsquo;s not about whether you get the right answer or not. It&rsquo;s all about the process you use to get your solution and whether you have a structured approach. Programming is very structured profession with a lot of semantics that need to be followed, so just throwing shit at the board and hoping it will stick is probably the worst thing you could do. And I definitely did that a few times just to say something to break the silence. Basically&hellip;don&rsquo;t do that and instead try to follow the steps I outlined above.</p>

<p>Best of luck, and feel free to email me if you have any other questions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/06/13/job-update/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-13T23:57:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/06/13/job-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since I&rsquo;ve blogged lately, but that&rsquo;s because I&rsquo;ve been knee deep in interviewing for the past three weeks and didn&rsquo;t have much to blog about. I have one more on-site interview left before I wrap up all my job applications and then I&rsquo;ll wait until I (hopefully) get an offer.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been a very interesting journey so far applying for jobs for the first time since graduating college five years ago. What I&rsquo;ve realized is times have changed and stealing a line from Mugato in Zoolander:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/job-update/mugatu.png"></p>

<h3>The Numbers</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be honest, before I applied for jobs, I thought my response rate would be ~30%. Because of this, I decided to shotgun approach the application process and shot out <strong>32 job applications</strong> and fielded a few recruiter calls as well. Overall, the results were pretty astonishing:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/job-update/stats.png"></p>

<p>I guess I had the percentage right, but the outcome wrong. 72% of the places I applied to, gave me at least a callback, which also meant I fielded somewhere between 20-30 thirty minute (10 &ndash; 15 hours) phone calls total just to get my foot in the door. I think one or two declined a follow up, and others I felt weren&rsquo;t a good fit so I politely declined continuing conversations. However, about 50% of all my applications proceeded with a technical screen or coding challenge, and 60% of those brought me on-site for an interview. Overall, that&rsquo;s a total of 10 on-site interviews, but unfortunately that has not panned out into 10 awesome offers. That information is something I will not disclose publicly, but I&rsquo;m optimistic that I&rsquo;ll have a great job by this time next week.</p>

<h3>So what&rsquo;s the Secret?</h3>

<p>Was it Hack Reactor? Was it my CS-related technical degree? Did my story resonate with employers? Or am I just a good programmer and never knew it?</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sure it was a combination of all of the above, but I&rsquo;ll never know exactly. I definitely feel like being a developer in San Francisco is like being a Tickle Me Elmo 10 years ago around Christmas time. The supply is low and the demand is high, and honestly, quoting one of my teachers at Hack Reactor: &ldquo;If you can write <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hello_world_program">&ldquo;Hello World&rdquo;</a> to a computer these days, you could probably get an interview.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I plan to follow up with a blog post about the three stages of programming interviews and what was successful and what failed. After going through so many, I feel like you could potentially &ldquo;cheat the system&rdquo; by simplying preparing for the types of questions they would ask. To give some context, I was given &ldquo;code Fibonacci&rdquo; four times in four different interviews. <strong>Check back next week for another update</strong>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meteor.js and Yelp OAuth Search]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/05/22/meteor-dot-js-and-yelp-oauth-search/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-22T18:07:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/05/22/meteor-dot-js-and-yelp-oauth-search</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Revisiting my MeetMeet web app, I thought I&rsquo;d share the code snippet for configuring Meteor.js to work with Yelp&rsquo;s search API. Meteor is still new and the smart packages are still being churned out every day, but one does not exist for Yelp search.</p>

<h4>The Pre-Reqs</h4>

<p>First things first, you&rsquo;ll need a Yelp developer account first, which can be found <a href="http://www.yelp.com/developers/documentation">here</a>. Once you sign up and get API keys, make sure you take down the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>Consumer Key</li>
<li>Consumer Secret</li>
<li>Token</li>
<li>Token Secret</li>
</ul>


<p>Then login to your mongo database with <code>meteor mongo</code> and run the following statement:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>Accounts.loginServiceConfiguration.remove({service: "yelp"});
</span><span class='line'>Accounts.loginServiceConfiguration.insert({
</span><span class='line'>  service: "yelp",
</span><span class='line'>  consumerKey: "YOUR_KEY_HERE",
</span><span class='line'>  consumerSecret: "YOUR_SECRET_HERE",
</span><span class='line'>  accessToken: "YOUR_TOKEN_HERE",
</span><span class='line'>  accessTokenSecret: "YOUR_TOKEN_SECRET"
</span><span class='line'>});</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This inserts the yelp service into the same collection as the other Meteor OAuth helpers.  Nothing gets stored on the user account for Yelp, but it&rsquo;s not good practice to have your credentials in source code.</p>

<h4>The Code</h4>

<p>I had to utilize Meteor&rsquo;s built in OAuth1 helpers and a little trial and error, but the finished code is below:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
<span class='line-number'>33</span>
<span class='line-number'>34</span>
<span class='line-number'>35</span>
<span class='line-number'>36</span>
<span class='line-number'>37</span>
<span class='line-number'>38</span>
<span class='line-number'>39</span>
<span class='line-number'>40</span>
<span class='line-number'>41</span>
<span class='line-number'>42</span>
<span class='line-number'>43</span>
<span class='line-number'>44</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">yelpQuery</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">search</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">isCategory</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">longitude</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">latitude</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;Yelp search for userId: &#39;</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">userId</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="s1">&#39;(search, isCategory, lng, lat) with vals (&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">search</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">isCategory</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">longitude</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">latitude</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;)&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Query OAUTH credentials (these are set manually)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">auth</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">Accounts</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">loginServiceConfiguration</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">findOne</span><span class="p">({</span><span class="nx">service</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;yelp&#39;</span><span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Add auth signature manually</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">auth</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;serviceProvider&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nx">signatureMethod</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s2">&quot;HMAC-SHA1&quot;</span> <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">accessor</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">consumerSecret</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">auth</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">consumerSecret</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">tokenSecret</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">auth</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">accessTokenSecret</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">},</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">parameters</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">{};</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Search term or categories query</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">isCategory</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">parameters</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">category_filter</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">search</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">else</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">parameters</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">term</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">search</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Set lat, lon location, if available (SF is default location)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">longitude</span> <span class="o">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class="nx">latitude</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">parameters</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">ll</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">latitude</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="s1">&#39;,&#39;</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="nx">longitude</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">else</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">parameters</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">location</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s1">&#39;San+Francisco&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Results limited to 5</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">parameters</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">limit</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Configure OAUTH parameters for REST call</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">parameters</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">oauth_consumer_key</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">auth</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">consumerKey</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">parameters</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">oauth_consumer_secret</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">auth</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">consumerSecret</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">parameters</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">oauth_token</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">auth</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">accessToken</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">parameters</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">oauth_signature_method</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">auth</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">serviceProvider</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">signatureMethod</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Create OAUTH1 headers to make request to Yelp API</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">oauthBinding</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">OAuth1Binding</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">auth</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">consumerKey</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">auth</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">consumerSecret</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;http://api.yelp.com/v2/search&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">oauthBinding</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">accessTokenSecret</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">auth</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">accessTokenSecret</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">headers</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">oauthBinding</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">_buildHeader</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Return data results only</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">oauthBinding</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">_call</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;GET&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;http://api.yelp.com/v2/search&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">headers</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">parameters</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">data</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h4>Input Parameters</h4>

<ul>
<li>search: Search term or category names</li>
<li>isCategory: Boolean stating whether &lsquo;search&rsquo; parameter is a category</li>
<li>longitude and latitude: Latitude and Longitude of user&rsquo;s location (optional)

<ul>
<li>Default location is statically set to San Francisco</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>You can use Yelp&rsquo;s provided sample program to test your API credentials work, but if everything works, you&rsquo;ll get back 5 yelp businesses as a javascript object.</p>

<p><em>SOON TO COME</em>: An mrt package!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Dreaded Job Search]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/05/20/the-dreaded-job-search/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-20T11:21:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/05/20/the-dreaded-job-search</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>The Serious Side</h3>

<p>Well, the day is finally upon us here at Hack Reactor. The dreaded job search! Dun dun dun dunnnnn.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.jvskc.org/UserFiles/Image/KeyboardFindJob.JPg" width="400" height="400"></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s funny how it felt like only yesterday I couldn&rsquo;t wait for this day to come. Now that it&rsquo;s here, I am overwhelmed by how many companies are out there looking for good engineers. Rather than start the shotgun approach of applying to as many companies as possible, I&rsquo;ve been spending the past few days cleaning up my blog and projects in preparation for &ldquo;Hiring Day&rdquo; this Thursday.</p>

<p>For the 25% returning visitor traffic (according to Google Analytics), you may/may not notice there are three (YES! Three!) new links in the sidebar.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://marklee22.github.io/resume">Resume</a></li>
<li><a href="http://marklee22.github.io/projects">Projects</a></li>
<li>And <a href="http://marklee22.github.io/about">About Me</a></li>
</ul>


<p>I felt like it was time to put myself out there in case potential employers were interested in hiring me.</p>

<h3>The Hilarious Side</h3>

<p>Earlier last week, one of the co-founders of Hack Reactor sent out an email to us to discourage us from applying to jobs. I&rsquo;m not going to include the entire email, but the email chain went like so:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/job_search/shawn_email.png"></p>

<p>And my response:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/job_search/mark_email.png"></p>

<p>I received many accolades from my colleagues for this. But in all seriousness, it&rsquo;s probably time to stop the jokes and start taking things a <em>little</em> bit more serious.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Hackathon]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/05/05/my-first-hackathon/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-05T14:43:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/05/05/my-first-hackathon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This weekend, we took some time off from the regular day-to-day and all went to a Hackathon called <a href="http://angelhack.com/">Angel Hack</a>. I went in as a team of two with my classmate Philip, and our idea was to create a random recipe generator that integrated with Instagram. We felt that our idea was simple enough to finish in 24 hours, as well as, creative enough to distinguish our product from the other apps generated in the past.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/angelhack/RecipeGram-mock.png" width="300" height="150">
<span class="caption text-center">Our whiteboard mocks the night before</span></p>

<h3>Tech Stack</h3>

<p>Due to time restraints, resource limitations, and it being our first Hackathon, we chose <a href="http://meteor.com/">Meteor.js</a>. Both Philip and I were familiar with Meteor and the single page app was necessary if we were going to build a mobile site.</p>

<h3>The Beginning</h3>

<p>We showed up at 9am at Yammer&rsquo;s HQ on 9th and Market. The building is also Twitter&rsquo;s HQ and it&rsquo;s clear that Twitter isn&rsquo;t the only one balling in that building. The first thought that came to my mind upon entering was A) What does Yammer do? B) How the hell do they make this much money?</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a mingle session where sponsors setup booths to encourage you to use their services. After briefly walking around and talking to the various sponsors about their APIs and listening to the prizes they had to offer, we decided to change our plan and use <a href="http://www.pearson.com/">Pearson&rsquo;s</a> API. However, shortly after going down that road, we scrapped it and switched back to <a href="http://www.yummly.com/">Yummly</a>. Philip was front-end and I was back-end, and we collaborated throughout the afternoon developing side-by-side.</p>

<h3>The Middle</h3>

<p>Around 8pm, we ran into a brick wall with our original idea. We had all our integrations working and pretty much had a finished product without styling, but the Instagram search capabilities were lacking what we wanted to do. To give you an example, say you were randomly given the recipe &ldquo;Amish Breakfast Casserole&rdquo;. NO ONE on Instagram tags their photo with &ldquo;#AmishBreakfastCasserole&rdquo; unfortunately, and there isn&rsquo;t a way to perform a Google-like image search using their API.</p>

<p>We quickly brainstormed for an alternative and thought we came up with our savior: <em>Search for each word and create an Instagram picture-like recipe</em>. For example, find the most popular picture for the terms &ldquo;Amish&rdquo;, &ldquo;Breakfast&rdquo;, and &ldquo;Casserole&rdquo; separately and display each one below the recipe. Once again Instagram&rsquo;s API search capabilities fucked us and is only capable of returning recent photos instead of most popular photos for a tag. Although some of the photos made sense (and were somewhat humorous), some 12 year old girl who tagged her photo with a million hashtags ruined our search algorithm.</p>

<h3>The End</h3>

<p>The good news is we got to go home and sleep in our own beds. The bad news is we scrapped our idea and decided not to submit it for presentation. I will however, show you the screenshots of our stopping point below and the code can be found <a href="http://github.com/marklee22/recipeGram">here</a>.</p>

<div class="center inline-block">
<img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/angelhack/RecipeGram-home.png" width="300" height="150">
<img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/angelhack/RecipeGram-recipe.png" width="300" height="150">
<img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/angelhack/RecipeGram-instagram.png" width="300" height="150">
<span class="caption text-center">Our actual screens</span>
</div>


<p>As you can see, we didn&rsquo;t style the application, but would have made it look nicer if we decided to present instead.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MeetMeet]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/04/30/meetmeet/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-30T23:51:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/04/30/meetmeet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ten days ago, I embarked on my first balls-to-the-wall hacking experience and I&rsquo;m pretty proud of the outcome.  It&rsquo;s a site I call (for now) &ldquo;MeetMeet&rdquo;, which can be viewed <a href="http://meeetmeet.meteor.com">here</a>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/meetmeet.png"></p>

<p>We were given 4 days to work on our personal project, but over our one week break, I thought it would be best to get a headstart after looking at my list of features I wanted to implement. I think the main lesson I learned is that the term &ldquo;MVP&rdquo; does not stand for &ldquo;MOST valuable product&rdquo;.  It stands for &ldquo;MINIMUM viable product&rdquo;.  However, I think I have a fully (yet a little buggy) web app built in <a href="http://www.meteor.com">Meteor.js</a>.</p>

<h1>What the app does</h1>

<p>This is an idea I&rsquo;ve had for a while that I never had time to pursue.  Originally, I actually wanted to make a native iOS app, but am now glad I made a somewhat-responsive web app instead. The amount of functionality built into 10 days is impressive by my standards, and I can only attribute Meteor&rsquo;s intuitive and easy to use framework for it. Enough technical jargon. Let&rsquo;s dive into the details.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s how it works (and there&rsquo;s a section on the site explaining this):</p>

<ol>
<li>Create an account</li>
<li>Hook up your Google Calendar and Facebook Friends</li>
<li>Select your meeting preferences</li>
<li>Pick who you want to meet from your Facebook Friends</li>
<li>Let MeetMeet auto schedule events based on &lsquo;mutually anonymous agreements&rsquo; and free time on your schedule</li>
</ol>


<p>A pretty basic and straightforward process that I can hopefully build more features for. I have declared it an alpha because I&rsquo;ve barely had time to test it fully, but from what I can tell, it should work (<strong>knock on wood</strong>).</p>

<p>Anyways, it&rsquo;s 12am now, I just deployed it, and I&rsquo;m the last one here at Hack Reactor. Feel free to sign up and check it out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why does this Blog Exist?]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/04/29/why-does-this-blog-exist/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-29T11:44:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/04/29/why-does-this-blog-exist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been receiving some feedback that my blog has become unreadable to friends/family who are not coders. During my enrollment, the purpose of my blog changed from documenting my actual journey to showcasing my skills as a developer. I should have maintained a balance between the two since the tags in the upper right allow readers to filter between the two.</p>

<p>Would I would suggest is using a filter to read what interests you:</p>

<ol>
<li>. Personal &ndash; Non-technical</li>
<li>. Programming &ndash; Technical</li>
</ol>


<h3>So What&rsquo;s New?</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m officially half way done with my program and the &ldquo;heavy lifting&rdquo; learning portion is now complete. The second half is more focused on personal and group projects while applying for jobs. It&rsquo;s crazy to think that it&rsquo;s been 6 weeks since I embarked on this adventure.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve realized that although I still live in San Francisco, I don&rsquo;t feel like it because so much of my time is spent either walking to/from class and working on projects. Luckily, I&rsquo;ve made a lot of friends here in the previous and current cohort. It kind of feels like college all over again with late nights spent in the computer lab. I&rsquo;ve had a few nights here and there where I&rsquo;ve seen my friends, and everytime it reminds me how much happier I am when I get the chance to see them. It&rsquo;s eerily similar to probably how patients in rehab feel.</p>

<h3>6 Week Reflections</h3>

<p>Because there hasn&rsquo;t been enough comedy in these posts, lets use some good ole self-deprecating humor of how my life has changed from living pretty to basically living off my savings. I&rsquo;m not saying my life is better or worse now, but I definitely live a more <strong>frugally sustainable</strong> lifestyle.</p>

<h4>Before</h4>

<ul>
<li>Paid for my muni pass</li>
<li>Never packed my lunch</li>
<li>Budgeted $200/month for random Amazon purchases</li>
<li>Went out 2-3 times a week</li>
<li>Aggressively dated</li>
<li>Frequented the grocery store</li>
</ul>


<h4>And now&hellip;</h4>

<ul>
<li>Walk/sneak on muni and have luckily not been ticketed (yet). Hopefully they don&rsquo;t read my blog.</li>
<li>Pack my lunch and/or dinner everyday</li>
<li>Resisting the urge to order things I don&rsquo;t truly need</li>
<li>Rarely drink or go out</li>
<li>Reminisce about dating stories with my classmates</li>
<li>Pickup fruit from Chinatown before class</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;ve gone from an average spending of $3200/month to less than $2000, which brings my actual living expenses to $800 or less excluding rent. Only now am I realizing I probably would have been a stellar accountant. Alright, time to get back to coding.  But I just want you all to know that I have a web app that I&rsquo;ve been working on the past 2 weeks that will allow us all to hangout more often!  Check back Wednesday May 1st!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backbone.js Tips]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/04/15/backbone-dot-js-tips/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-15T16:45:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/04/15/backbone-dot-js-tips</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve spent a lot of time the past couple of weeks learning a lot of new languages, technologies, and concepts.  One that I have  particularly been focusing on is <a href="">Backbone.js</a>, which is a fairly complicated library for such a small amount of code.  I just want to make it clear that this is not a post about how Backbone works, but instead is meant more as tips or &ldquo;gotchas&rdquo; for what I found difficult learning Backbone from scratch.</p>

<h3>Break out your code</h3>

<p>Backbone forces you to provide structure around your javascript code.  You might as well go the extra step and create a standard folder structure to separate each Class because it&rsquo;s a good habit to have.  I set up a simple folder structure before I start every project for models, collections, and views to make includes easier.</p>

<div class="aligncenter">
  <img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/backbone-tips/backbone-files.png">
  <img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/backbone-tips/backbone-files2.png">
</div>


<h3>You should know Underscore.js</h3>

<p>Backbone is written by the same developer who wrote <a href="">Underscore.js</a> and the majority of the Underscore functionality has been rolled into Backbone for models and collections.  It&rsquo;s worth the hour or so to study Underscore to help utilize these helpers instead of writing your own for loops and callbacks.</p>

<h3>Collections cannot hold attributes/properties</h3>

<p>I learned this the hard way, but you cannot call <code>this.set('attribute') = 'blah'</code> on a collection.  Collections are meant only to hold models and you&rsquo;ll get various errors if you try and call set/get methods on collections.</p>

<h3>Use triggers when children models need to communicate with the parent/grandparent</h3>

<p>I spent the good first few hours asking myself &ldquo;how can I get that model to do something based on another model?&rdquo;.  With several layers of models and collections, it&rsquo;s hard to picture how a lower tiered model communicates up the event chain.  Well, Backbone uses events and triggers to accomplish this.</p>

<p>Say I have an app model that holds a collection of card models.  In order for card to communicate with app, my collection would have a function that evaluates the state of a card or cards, and trigger an event if that condition is met.  Then in the app model, I would listen for that specific event to fire, and specify a callback to perform some action on my app.</p>

<p>Using my Blackjack App as an example, the app (model) listens for a player hand (collection), which checks each card (model) to determine if a player has blackjack or loses.  See the example below:</p>

<p>Hand Collection function to evaluate a player&rsquo;s total score</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">check</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="o">-&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="err">@</span><span class="nx">length</span> <span class="nx">is</span> <span class="mi">2</span> <span class="nx">and</span> <span class="err">@</span><span class="nx">scores</span><span class="p">()[</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="nx">is</span> <span class="mi">21</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="err">@</span><span class="nx">trigger</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;blackjack&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="err">@</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">else</span> <span class="k">if</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="err">@</span><span class="nx">scores</span><span class="p">().</span><span class="nx">every</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">score</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">-&gt;</span> <span class="nx">score</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="mi">21</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="err">@</span><span class="nx">trigger</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;lose&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="err">@</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The App Model that listens for the &lsquo;lose&rsquo; and &lsquo;blackjack&rsquo; events with associated callbacks</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'>  <span class="err">@</span><span class="nx">get</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;playerHand&#39;</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">on</span> <span class="s1">&#39;lose&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="err">@</span><span class="nx">gameOver</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="k">this</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="err">@</span><span class="nx">get</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;playerHand&#39;</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">on</span> <span class="s1">&#39;blackjack&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="err">@</span><span class="nx">blackJack</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="k">this</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>jQuery event handlers are only initiated once</h3>

<p>When your view is initialized, any event handlers declared in your events hash or initialize function will only be initialized once and inserted into the DOM.  If you end up deleting or replacing your html in your render function (For example: calling <code>this.$el.html([some rendered html]))</code>), your jQuery event handlers will be blown away.  In order to preserve these handlers, you would have to re-create them when you re-render your page.  A simple alternative to solve this however is to call <code>this.$el.children().detach()</code> to safely detach and reattach your jQuery children event handlers.</p>

<h3>Collection.fetch() resets your collection</h3>

<p>Backbone has implemented code that uses jQuery.ajax.  If you&rsquo;re switching over to Backbone models and have previous ajax calls defined, you&rsquo;ll have to utilize the url property on your Collection/Models and call fetch() to pull the data down from the server.  The one thing I discovered is everytime you fetch your data from the server, the default action is to reset the collection.  I believe you can get around this by setting some flags in your options hash and/or defining your own Collection.parse function.  In general though, it&rsquo;s best to fetch once and sync data thereafter rather than fetching multiple times from your server.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>That&rsquo;s all from me (for now).  Hopefully someone will find this useful because Backbone is a tough concept to learn.  By no means am I an expert with Backbone, but I&rsquo;m going to continue to practice more with it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blackjack: Backbone + CoffeeScript]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/04/08/blackjack-backbone-plus-coffeescript/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-08T16:09:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/04/08/blackjack-backbone-plus-coffeescript</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="float-right" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/blackjack/specs.png" width="400" height="360">
With today&rsquo;s post, I bring to you my first interactive game written entirely in javascript.  As always if you&rsquo;re non-technical, feel free to jump straight to the bottom of this post to see the app.  I really enjoyed this project because I was able to accomplish three things I&rsquo;ve been meaning to spend more time on:</p>

<ul>
<li>Get more practice with <a href="http://backbonejs.org" title="Backbone.js">Backbone.js</a></li>
<li>Play around with <a href="http://coffeescript.org/" title="CoffeeScript">CoffeeScript</a></li>
<li>Develop code using a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test-driven_development" title="TDD">test driven strategy</a> (TDD)</li>
</ul>


<h3>TDD</h3>

<p>Testing is a newfound concept for me when it comes to programming, but I am constantly improving my ability to write good test coverage for all my projects here.  For this project specifically, I decided to use <a href="http://pivotal.github.io/jasmine/" title="Jasmine">Jasmine</a> as my testing suite.  I found two things key to writing tests for Backbone:</p>

<ul>
<li>Learn how spies work.  Seriously, it is the key to the puzzle</li>
<li>Build my tests from the bottom up, meaning I focus on the lowest level models first and proceed up the model chain</li>
</ul>


<p>What I&rsquo;m finding out here at Hack Reactor is that no one enjoys testing except me.  I think it&rsquo;s one part OCD and one part understanding that it&rsquo;s the agile way.  I feel like despite it doubled my implementation time, it made me think long and hard about how the application should work.  Once I figured out how spies work and where to initialize them, I was quickly moving through additional tests involving triggers and chained function calls.</p>

<h3>CoffeeScript vs Javascript</h3>

<p>In case you&rsquo;ve never heard of CoffeeScript, it is quintessentially what C is to Assembly.  It abstracts the javascript language and provides several helpers or &ldquo;shortcuts&rdquo; that eventually compiles into javascript code.  I think using CoffeeScript or Javascript is simply a matter of taste.  Although I enjoyed writing less lines of code and <em>not</em> having to use semi-colons.  The browser still runs on javascript, and when something breaks, I have to dig through the compiled JS files to backtrace what line of CoffeeScript is failing.  <em>Bottom line though</em>: You should probably be familiar with both.</p>

<p>I definitely see the advantages of writing CoffeeScript, and wouldn&rsquo;t be surprised if more and more companies use it in the future.  I&rsquo;m just not a fan of optional parentheses and replacing &lsquo;this&rsquo; with &lsquo;@&rsquo;.  It doesn&rsquo;t look right to me yet coming from years of coding in C++, Java, and PHP, but over time I could see myself changing my sentiment.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s look at a basic example here of the hit() method for a Hand.</p>

<h5>CoffeeScript</h5>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='coffeescript'><span class='line'>  <span class="nv">hit: </span><span class="nf">-&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">@add</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">@deck</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">pop</span><span class="p">()).</span><span class="nx">last</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="k">unless</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">@scores</span><span class="p">().</span><span class="nx">every</span> <span class="nf">(score) -&gt;</span> <span class="nx">score</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="mi">21</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h5>Javascript Equivalent</h5>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='js'><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">Hand</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">prototype</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">hit</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="o">!</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">scores</span><span class="p">().</span><span class="nx">every</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">score</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">score</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="mi">21</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">})))</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="k">return</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">add</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">deck</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">pop</span><span class="p">()).</span><span class="nx">last</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>As you can see CoffeeScript is concise, clean, and less characters overall.  I&rsquo;m just not &lsquo;fluent&rsquo; in the language yet, so in my brain I am converting the CoffeeScript to javascript anyways.</p>

<h3>Backbone Models/Collections/Views</h3>

<p>Overall, there are three model classes in play here:</p>

<ol>
<li> App &ndash; Top level model that controls the game functionality with the player/dealer</li>
<li> Deck &ndash; Collection of 52 unique Card models</li>
<li> DiscardPile &ndash; Collection of Card models that is initially empty for holding all previously played cards</li>
<li> Hand &ndash; Collection of Cards with helper methods like hit, stand, getScore, etc.</li>
<li> Card &ndash; Base model representing a card (suit and value)</li>
</ol>


<p>Since our app will only display the app, hand, and cards, I only needed View classes for those models.  I feel the hardest part about learning Backbone is to understand what code goes where, and once you engrain the idea that you should avoid logic in views, it becomes much easier to visualize the file structure.</p>

<p>I found testing to be a big help for this project specifically.  Normally, I&rsquo;d make a code change, refresh the web browser, and simulate the user functionality I implemented manually.  With extensive tests, I simply changed that process to verify all my tests are still passing in case I broke something unexpectedly.  Of course at the end, I decided to spend a few hours cleaning up the UX/UI to polish it up.  It&rsquo;s amazing how 1-2 hours of CSS work + images + animations can make something look that much better.  I used to hate doing CSS, but I&rsquo;m starting to grow fond of it as it is the final layer of polish to every application.  I also decided to use sprites for the card images instead of individual images.  It&rsquo;s an interesting concept that I learned reading a blog in <a href="http://reddit.com/r/programming" title="Programming">reddit programming</a> which is a concept I&rsquo;m sure will come in handy in the future!</p>

<h3>Now for the app itself!</h3>

<p>This is a basic Blackjack application.  It does not support <em>betting</em> (unfortunately), <em>splits</em>, or <em>dealer insurance</em>.  I hope you enjoy this and eventually I will release the gist when the repo is public after my program at Hack Reactor is complete.  Check back soon!</p>

<div id="blackjackApp">
  <script src="http://marklee22.github.io/javascripts/posts/blackjack/models/Card.js"></script>
  <script src="http://marklee22.github.io/javascripts/posts/blackjack/models/Hand.js"></script>
  <script src="http://marklee22.github.io/javascripts/posts/blackjack/models/DiscardPile.js"></script>
  <script src="http://marklee22.github.io/javascripts/posts/blackjack/models/Deck.js"></script>
  <script src="http://marklee22.github.io/javascripts/posts/blackjack/models/App.js"></script>
  <script src="http://marklee22.github.io/javascripts/posts/blackjack/views/CardView.js"></script>
  <script src="http://marklee22.github.io/javascripts/posts/blackjack/views/HandView.js"></script>
  <script src="http://marklee22.github.io/javascripts/posts/blackjack/views/AppView.js"></script>
  <script src="http://marklee22.github.io/javascripts/posts/blackjack/main.js"></script>
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js Chat Server]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/nodejs-chat-server/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-02T12:43:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/nodejs-chat-server</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I bring to you my first web interactive project that I call &#8220;ChatBot&#8221;.  This is an application that I built from the ground up using Javascript/jQuery/ajax on the front-end, and <a href="http://nodejs.org/">Node.js</a> on the backend.  Using the free and easy-to-use hosting platform <a href="heroku.com">Heroku</a>, you can browse to my web app right now <a class="big" href="http://infinite-caverns-3250.herokuapp.com/">here!</a></p>


<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/chatbot-1.png" width="500" height="500"></p>

<h3>So How Does it Work (from a technical standpoint)?</h3>


<ol>
  <li>A user browses to the website and subsequently submits an HTTP request</li>
  <li>Node server processes request and serves up HTML/JS/CSS pages</li>
  <li>jQuery/Javascript binds event handlers and callbacks to various DOM nodes and actions</li>
  <li>Using AJAX, Javascript periodically polls the server for new messages</li>
</ol>


<h3>Alright Mark, but what about for all us non-programmers?</h3>


<p>Right.  The features of what I implemented.  Basically, this is the next GoogleTalk in the making&#8230;  Well, not really, but it was a great project for learning more about ajax, Node.js, and the client-server programming paradigm.  A couple features that I implemented:</p>


<ul>
  <li>Room and Friend list updates dynamically with who has submitted chats</li>
  <li>Multiple chat rooms are supported, however, it has to be run manually (for now) by browsing to a url like http://infinite-caverns-3250.herokuapp.com/classes/&lt;roomName&gt;</li>
  <li>Chat room filtering of messages</li>
  <li>&#8220;Friend list&#8221; highlighting</li>
  <li>And of course, the ability to chat with others over the web</li>
</ul>


<p>Here is a small snippet of the client side send message function:</p>




<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='js'><span class='line'><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">sendMessage</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">username</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">message</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">roomname</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Construct the message option to send to the server</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">message</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="s1">&#39;username&#39;</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nb">document</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">username</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="s1">&#39;text&#39;</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">message</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="s1">&#39;roomname&#39;</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">roomname</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Send the message to the server via ajax</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">ajax</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;http://&#39;</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="nb">window</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">location</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">host</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="s1">&#39;/classes/messages&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">type</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;POST&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">contentType</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;json&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">data</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">JSON</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">stringify</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">message</span><span class="p">),</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">error</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">xhr</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">status</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">msg</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;POST ERROR!&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">},</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">success</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">msg</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;POST SUCCESS!&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">};</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>




<p>Then on the server-side, I have a request handler function that handles JSON POST requests:</p>




<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
<span class='line-number'>33</span>
<span class='line-number'>34</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='js'><span class='line'><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">handleRequest</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">request</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">response</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">headers</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">statusCode</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">fileName</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">retData</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s1">&#39;&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">urlPath</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">require</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;url&#39;</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">parse</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">request</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">url</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">path</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">urlPath</span> <span class="o">===</span> <span class="s1">&#39;/&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">statusCode</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">200</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">headers</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;Content-Type&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s1">&#39;text/html&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">retData</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">ejs</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">render</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">indexTemplate</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span> <span class="k">else</span> <span class="k">if</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">request</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">method</span> <span class="o">===</span> <span class="s1">&#39;POST&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">statusCode</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">200</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">retData</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;\n&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">data</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s1">&#39;&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="c1">// Buffer the post request&#39;s data</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">request</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">on</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;data&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">chunk</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">data</span> <span class="o">+=</span> <span class="nx">chunk</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="c1">// Process request now that the request has been completed</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">request</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">on</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;end&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">message</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">JSON</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">parse</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">data</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="c1">// console.log(&#39;New Message: &#39;,message);</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="c1">// Only maintain 20 messages</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="k">if</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">messages</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">length</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="mi">20</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="nx">messages</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">shift</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">message</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;createdAt&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nb">Date</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">message</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;updatedAt&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nb">Date</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">messages</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">push</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">message</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="c1">// console.log(messages);</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Blog!]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/03/28/new-blog/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T22:14:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/03/28/new-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Given my new web skills, I decided to switch blogs!  Although, Wordpress was a great way to start my blogging career, I wanted something a little more customizable to allow me to include some of the projects I&#8217;ve been working on lately.  I switched to <a href="http://www.octopress.org">Octopress</a>, which is based on the <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll blog static-page framework</a>.</p>


<p>  I&rsquo;m now using github to host my blog which also allows free hosting.  I&rsquo;ve only just started playing around with what Octopress has to offer, but so far I&rsquo;m impressed how easy it was to setup.  Overall, it probably took me 3-4 hours to get everything setup and migrated.  I guess the one drawback is I lost the nifty spell checker before I post, so maybe if I&rsquo;m really bored, I&rsquo;ll work on a javascript or Ruby plugin to catch any errors in the future.</p>

<p>In case you just found my blog, below is what it used to look like.  As you can see it&#8217;s boring, shows little customization, and says I am both lonely and working from home, which is now no longer the case!</p>


<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/new-blog-1.png" width="800" height="800"></p>

<p><p/></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Week Down, 11 More to Go]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/03/18/one-week-down-11-more-to-go/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/03/18/one-week-down-11-more-to-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
It&#8217;s been a while since I last posted.&#8211;my apologies. I&#8217;ve removed the day counter because I no longer get to sit next to the BeastMode calendar everyday to visually track my days of unemployment. It&#8217;s Monday now (I think), which is actually midweek for us here at Hack Reactor. Overall, the experience has been good so far. We&#8217;ve gone through technologies, languages, and concepts at a blazing speed. I find most of the coursework to be a good refresherfor what I&#8217;ve already learned in the past, but italso fills in gaps for what I missed.
</p>




<p>
The practice of just coding for hours each day has always been my primary motivator for joining this class, and so far there has been plenty. Here we have a very regimented schedule and more often than not Friday to Wednesday, my daily schedule is as follows:
<ul>
    <li><span style="line-height:16px;">8am: Wake up</span></li>
    <li>9am: Arrive at Hack Reactor for breakfast</li>
    <li>9:15am-1pm: Code</li>
    <li><span style="color:#339966;">1pm-2pm: Lunch (fri, sun, tues we get 1 hour for the gym)</span></li>
    <li>2pm-5:30pm: Code</li>
    <li><span style="color:#339966;">5:30pm-6:30pm: Dinner</span></li>
    <li>6:30pm-8pm: Lecture, Review, Feedback</li>
    <li>8pm-11pm (optional): Continue on class projects, work on side projects, study, etc.</li>
</ul>
I&#8217;ve gone ahead and highlighted the times when I&#8217;m free in case any of you readers want to grab lunch or dinner one of these days. Thursdays are my off day, so if you really miss me, then plan something then.
</p>




<p>
In this program, we are asked to spend 1-2 weeks on a side project, and I have a couple ideas of what I want to build. If anyone has a (web) tool they wish they had, but doesn&#8217;t exist or is poorly implemented, feel free to email me.
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hack Reactor: Student Presentation]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/03/18/hack-reactor-student-presentation/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/03/18/hack-reactor-student-presentation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
We have student presentations here, where a student gives a 5 minute presentation on something they found interesting that they want to present to the class. When they were taking volunteers, I had an itch on my eyebrow, which was mistakenly taken as a hand raise. So now I&#8217;m writing up a little excerpt on what I will be presenting later today so I can shamelessly promote my blog.
</p>




<div class="aligncenter">
  <img src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/student-presentation-1.png" width="255" height="300">
  <span class="caption">&#8220;Bad Luck Brian&#8221;</span>
</div>




<p>
The topic of my presentation is<strong>jQuery-menu-aim</strong><strong>and Helpful Web Resources</strong>. I know what you&#8217;re already thinking: &#8220;What does that exactly mean?&#8221;&#8211;good question.
</p>




<p>
Well, for all the non-technical people, jQuery is a utility library developed by really really ridiculously smart people to simplify how we select &#8220;stuff&#8221; on web pages via code. I know what you&#8217;re thinking now: &#8220;Yes, that&#8217;s cool and all, but what about menu aim?&#8221; Well, menu-aim is like a sub-utility library built using jQuery that does even more cool and crazy stuff. Then that developer rolls it into a package, says &#8220;hey guys, look what I did!&#8221;, and other developers can now use it instead of rewriting that functionality from scratch.
</p>




<p>Rather than typing out a technical explanation of how it works, I&#8217;ll perform some &#8220;blog-ception&#8221; and just link the blog post I read that describes it better than I could ever, which is <a href="http://bjk5.com/post/44698559168/breaking-down-amazons-mega-dropdown" target="_blank">here</a>. For those who want the jQuery plugin, click <a href="https://github.com/kamens/jQuery-menu-aim" target="_blank">here</a>.
</p>




<p>
As for the helpful web resources, well, it&#8217;s a compilation of cool resources I&#8217;ve found while browsing the interwebs that I feel can be helpful to other new and existing developers.
<ul>
    <li><a href="http://overapi.com/" target="_blank">A list of all the APIs for web languages</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/" target="_blank">Programming sub-reddit</a> (follow this sub)</li>
    <li><a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/cscareerquestions/" target="_blank">CScareerquestions sub-reddit</a> (look into the posts to answer your questions)</li>
    <li><a href="http://lastpass.com" target="_blank">LastPass</a> - By far my favorite web tool</li>
</ul>
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 7: Boy, That Escalated Quickly]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/03/05/day-7-boy-that-escalated-quickly/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/03/05/day-7-boy-that-escalated-quickly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="aligncenter">
  <img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/boy-that-escalated-quickly-1.png" width="550" height="280" title="'Test caption'" >
  <span class="caption">The only way to describe how I truly feel</span>
</div>




<p>
<span style="line-height:1.5;">I haven&#8217;t posted in a while, and that&#8217;s simply because that meetup I went to last Thursday has snowballed into me actually enrolling in the class. I guess the title of my blog will be misleading now and I should update it to reflect the fact that for the next 3 months, I&#8217;ll be coding extensively at this place called</span><a style="line-height:1.5;" title="Hack Reactor Site" href="http://www.hackreactor.com" target="_blank">Hack Reactor</a>.
</p>




<p>
This is a huge investment on my part, and I&#8217;d be lying if I didn&#8217;t say the financial ramifications weren&#8217;t extremely mind rattling. After much thought, a google spreadsheet listing the costs, and several conversations with the teachers, alums, and fellow friends in the industry, I came to a conclusion&#8230;
</p>




<p>
<strong>Bottom line:</strong>With or without the class, I&#8217;d get to the end of the tunnel and be a sufficient programmer.
</p>




<p>
It&#8217;s just that my growth would be exponential under a regimented schedule versus learning on my own. In the grand scheme of things money-wise, it comes out to either 3 months with the course or 9 months self-taught learning. Being the methodical, motivated, and over-analytical bastard I am, I decided that enrolling would allow me to <span style="text-decoration:underline;">learn more</span>, as well as, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">learn faster</span>. In essence, this was the most EFFICIENT solution, but probably not the SMARTESTsolution. If you&#8217;re part of my family, you probably heavily leaned towards the latter (and that&#8217;s an understatement). If you&#8217;re anyone else, you probably said &#8220;jesus, that&#8217;s a lot of dough&#8221;, but I support your decision.
</p>




<p>
Which brings me to my last point. This course is 60 hours a week (plus) and 6 days a week with only Wednesdays as the off day. There&#8217;s a good (and almost certain) chance my social life will become non-existent. I apologize ahead of time if I stop updating this blog since I start this Friday and finish June 6th. I&#8217;ll do my best to keep this updated just so you can feel like I&#8217;m still part of your lives.
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 5: New Month! First week complete]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/03/02/day-5-new-month-first-week-complete/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/03/02/day-5-new-month-first-week-complete</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
It&#8217;s a new month and my unemployment officially begins today. Hooray? Before I give a recap of what I&#8217;ve learned this week, I want to first talk about a meetup I went to last night. The meetup was called<a href="http://www.sfruby.info/events/104937692/">Q&amp;A with Alums from Coding Schools &amp; mingle</a>, which was basically a panel of people who enrolled in these 12 week programming bootcamps to become competent Rails/Python/Javascript developers. This was first recommended to me by my roommate who is a Ruby and Rails enthusiast, but the takeaway I got from it was that anyone can enroll in one of these schools and eventually get a job as a developer. Obviously, it&#8217;s more dependent on the person than the program, but all the interviewees were from non-programming backgrounds and now have full-time jobs in the industry. Pretty cool stuff if you ask me.
</p>


<p>
Now back to the updates. With every new month, comes a new &#8220;BeastMode&#8221; picture, so here it is courtesy of Adam Eversole:
</p>


<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/march-beast-mode.png" width="225" height="300"></p>

<p>
The rest of my week was spent learning CSS and cleaning up my project site&#8217;s look and feel. It&#8217;s crazy how much work can be dedicated to frontend styling, but it&#8217;s such a necessary component for having something you&#8217;re confident in showing to people. Other than that, I&#8217;ve been doing a lot of the opposite of the title of this blog: socializing and not-working-as-much-as-I&#8217;d-like. One of my best friends recently got back from the Peace Core and we had a welcome back party for him. I also went out for a few beers for trivia and darts with a few teammates on my soccer team. I think it&#8217;s important to still maintain a healthy balance of work and fun, so I guess this blog won&#8217;t be completely about the overhyped loneliness I seem to emphasize.
</p>


<p>
I can&#8217;t end this post like that, so I want to also say that I have an information interview with one of the teachers from Hack Reactor to try and figure out what&#8217;s the most efficient way to achieve my goal. An update to come shortly with my findings!
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 4: MacBook Acquired!]]></title>
    <link href="http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/02/28/day-4-macbook-acquired/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://marklee22.github.io/blog/2013/02/28/day-4-macbook-acquired</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
Great news! My MacBook arrived yesterday and thanks to Apple&#8217;s awesome time machine restoration, I was up and running in no time with all my work transferred seamlessly. There were some missing packages that seemed to not have transferred properly or needed to be updated, but a shout out to <a title="Homebrew" href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;cad=rja&amp;ved=0CDYQFjAA&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fmxcl.github.com%2Fhomebrew%2F&amp;ei=s5gvUYv1LIGriAKDw4G4CA&amp;usg=AFQjCNF6OlsT382KquSbQwpnH6G5Rc0bqQ&amp;sig2=v2-VmpsWttwg2Bgf3mhelw&amp;bvm=bv.43148975,d.cGE" target="_blank">homebrew</a> for their awesome package manager.
</p>


<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/macbook-1.png" width="300" height="225"></p>

<p>
I&#8217;m hitting the ground running now and resumed the task of building up my github profile with various projects. I&#8217;m open to requests if anyone has any ideas for a site they need/want made.
</p>


<p><img class="center" src="http://marklee22.github.io/images/posts/macbook-2.png" width="300" height="224"></p>

<p>
Also, beware that every update from here on out will most likely be technical jargon along the lines of how &#8220;I nearly threw my computer out the window trying to figure out this Rails concept&#8221;. Just know&#8230;you&#8217;ve now been warned!
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
